{
    "id": "0f05e8ddc66342378cf0e5760d6b5b6a",
    "title": "Present Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "My parents ……………………….. near Chennai.",
            "description": "We use the simple present to talk about permanent situations.",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "are living",
                "have lived"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………….. my parents twice a month.",
            "description": "The simple present tense is used to talk about things that happen regularly.",
            "answers": [
                "visit",
                "am visiting",
                "have visited"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "‘What are you doing there?’ ‘I …………………………….. TV.’",
            "description": "We use the present continuous tense to talk about actions or events that are going on around now.",
            "answers": [
                "watch",
                "am watching",
                "have watched"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Watch carefully. First I …………………………. a cucumber and …………………………. it into small pieces.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about a series of actions that are completed as we speak.",
            "answers": [
                "am taking, am cutting",
                "take, cut",
                "am taking, cut"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I will follow you wherever you ……………………………..",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a simple present tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will go",
                "are going",
                "go"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I will call you if I ………………………… time.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a simple present tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "get",
                "am getting",
                "have got"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "What ………………………. snakes …………………….?",
            "description": "The simple present tense is used to talk about permanent situations.",
            "answers": [
                "do, eat",
                "are, eating",
                "are, eat"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "How ………………………… I ……………………… to the airport?",
            "description": "The simple present tense is used when we ask for and give directions.",
            "answers": [
                "do, get",
                "am, getting",
                "do, getting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………. this fragrance very much.",
            "description": "The verb like is not normally used in the continuous form.",
            "answers": [
                "like",
                "am liking",
                "have liked"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will hit anybody who ………………………………. me names.",
            "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, we use a simple present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "calls",
                "is calling",
                "has called"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Why …………………………. she ……………………….. on the table?",
            "description": "The present continuous is usually used to talk about temporary situations",
            "answers": [
                "does, stand",
                "is, standing",
                "does, standing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The temple …………………………. on a hill outside the town.",
            "description": "The present simple is used to talk about permanent situations.",
            "answers": [
                "is standing",
                "has stood",
                "stands"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}